<root><div type="entry"><head><pb n="74"/>Christmas at West Overton.</head>

<p>On the night before mother + J.F.O. would place plates
on the living room table, and would find them on Xmas morning
heaped with fancy cakes, dried cherries + candies!
	
Also, on the night before, mother would place a plate of oats on
the basement porch bench, and
on Xmas morning the plate would be empty but one-half dollar would be there!</p>

<p>No gifts. No Christmas tree. They would attend Christmas service at the Mennonite Church at Alverton and have a special Xmas dinner at </p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="75"/>home after the Service.</head>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="76"/>New Year's Eve at Overton</head>

<p>There would be a merry company gathered in the home, awaiting the coming of the patron Saint Belschnickel!</p>

<p>Ide Would finally come, + throw nuts out for all</p>

<p>When little, mother was afraid of him. Ide was so big + qu???. She would stick close to Anna Leighty .</p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="89"/>Mothers duties, when a little girl,+ later</head>

<p>Would keep water pitcher on G+JFO's wash-stand full: also would keep drinking water pitcher filled. G+JFO always wanted pitchers full.</p>

<p>Later, would start living room grate fire each morning. - bringing up shavings from below + bringing in coal from the rear porch, second floor (had kept filled there by ??). Would lift ashes + place ??? on back porch (to be carried off by ???) </p>

<p>Would milk, getting up long before daylight + milking by lantern light. After 15 yrs of age, didnt have this to do.</p>

<p>Mrs. Fox taught her how to bake. Washing woman taught her howto wash; then When she knew how, she didnt have to do it.</p>

<p>Would sweep + dust on the 2nd, 3rd floors; Would ??? the big porch floor + scour the threshold stone!</p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="90"/>C.S.R.O. history + incidents</head>

<p>When nightman at W. 0. w'ill?, once he by mistake took a jug containing concentrated dye, used in washing (a midnight lunch + a jug of home-made
beer was always set out for him) He drank from the dye jug but as soon as he discovered it, he drank milk which prevented poisoning</p>

<p>When watchmen at Broadford, once all alligator was set out for him in his midnight
lunch. However he was wise, + didnt mistake it for fish? + eatit!</p>

<p>C.S.R.O. worked at Broadford twice .
(1) During + near close of Cine? bar, 1865, was watchman, lived at the old stone house near the River, where Jacob S.O.
had lived. Suceeded by A.S. Justman</p>

<p><pb n="91"/>(2) From late '67 to early '69, when he was in the Bfd Distillery.
He lived in a second floor room in the hash? house on the H.O. Justman place, and boarded at the H.O.J. house, where Mrs. Chain? ran a boarding house.</p>

<p>While there, Uncle Clay came to Bfd, + lived in the hashabaugh? house across the street, but boarded with Mrs. Chain? in the H.O.J. house.</p>

<p>A.O.J. + ??? O.J. lived in H.O.J. house,  as had Sr. Porter.?</p>

<p>Upon leaving Bfd second time,Uncle Cris S.R.O. worked in W.O. distillery, + boarded with Granpap O.
However he was ill with fever at his own home in Jan. '70 when GFO died.</p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="92"/>Jan. 15, 1870 - 6a.m.)</head>

<p>Grandpap O. died suddenly from a stroke, having gone to outhouse with lantern before breakfast.
?? ??? him + found him there, having fallen off upon entering outhouse.</p>

<p>He was 85 years 9 months of age.
----------------------------------------------
At ?? he had had pains in back of his head, but seemed in his usual health, + on preceding evening he had p??? q??? with Chester Booker.</p>

<p>Father + C.S.O. had been receiving Royal Area decree in Chapter Masonry at Gbg night before + were riding horseback home next morning when they heard of his health, at top of hill at ??</p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="141"/>My dear Sister:</head>

<p>We are deeply shocked and pained to hear of the death of Grace. We had heard some time ago that she was ailing but presumed she had recovered.</p>

<p>I am afraid it will not be possible for any of us to attend her funeral, as we are having so much trouble in the Coke region.</p>

<p>Your loss is a great one, but it is what we all have to ?? to. Ada ?? ?? tender sympathy and much love</p>

<p>Affectionately yours</p>

<p>Clay</p>

<p>Apl 5/94</p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="147"/>May 26. 1902</head>

<p>Uncle Clay sent mother check for 3.000$ to buy lot (195' by 225') on Bealle Ave, Wooster, Ohio, and wrote</p>

<p>"My dear Maria</p>

<p>You can go ahead and build you house and I will furnish the money as needed. I enclose check to pay for the lot.</p>

<p>Always yours</p>

<p>Clay</p>

<p>May 26 / 1902"</p>

</div><div type="entry"><head><pb n="159"/>Crock Cheese</head>

<p>Put thick milk in a large pot.
Heat and remove curds with skimmer.
Put sauce in cheese cloth + drain dry.
Then place sauce in crock + ?? by hand the cheese inside the cloth.</p>

<p>Then place in flat 1/2 gallon crock, tying a cloth over the top of the crock and placing in a harm? place.</p>

<p>Stir each day. After 3 days or more when it commences to have an odor, put butter in a skillet on the stove + place cheese in it, with a little salt sprinkled over the cheese and with half a cup of cream added.</p>

<p>Then heat until all dissolved and smooth, then place in a crock to ??.</p></div>
</root>